## Jacob Clapper

clapperpianist@gmail.com · Jamaica Plain, MA · <u>linkedIn</u> · <u>github.com</u> · <u>portfolio</u>

As a creative, focused, and diligent Software Engineer, I strive to develop full stack applications that are intuitive and efficient. My background as a teacher and pianist has given me the ability to manage and prioritize multiple obligations . I have developed necessary communication skills to collaborate as a team and also work independently. It is with this experience that I am able to build creative solutions that build community and increase productivity.

**Skills** JavaScript, Vanilla Javascript, React.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Heroku, Express, liquid, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Python 3.7, Git, GitHub, JQuery, PostgreSQL, Trello, Postman, Canva

## **SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS**

## Harmony Haven Github: Client API

August 2022

- Hosted on Heroku
- Wireframes and planned UI design of application using Canva
- Developed an MVP before moving to final production
- Utilized MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js to build a full stack application with full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and API back-end and a front-end client
- Made frequent commits using Git control throughout the production of application
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections
- Used seeded data for models

### Freelancr Github: Client - API

August 2022

- Hosted on Heroku
- Wireframes and planned UI design of application using Canva
- Developed an MVP before moving to final production
- Utilized MERN to build a full stack application with CRUD operations with API back-end and a front-end client
- Collaborated as a team making frequent commits using Git control throughout the production of application
- Used seeded data for models and subdocuments

## Music Lesson and Assignment Tracker github

**July 2022** 

- Wireframes and planned UI design of application using Canva
- Developed an MVP before moving to final production
- Utilized MERN to build a full stack application with CRUD operations
- Made frequent commits using Git control throughout the production of application
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections
- Deployed the web application to a remote server using <u>heroku</u>

Memory Game github

June 2022

• Used Vanilla Javascript, CSS3, and HTML5 and DOM manipulation to create a memory card matching game

• Utilized Javascript and Vanilla Javascript in creating object oriented function

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## All Souls Unitarian Universalist Church, Music Director

August 2015 - Current

- Collaborate with the minister or other service leaders in the creation of worship services.
- Choose anthems and hymns, in consultation with ministers/service leaders.
- Rehearse and direct choir on a Christmas Eve Service.
- Provide piano music for the Sunday services September through June with one Sunday off per month.

# **Curry College**, Collaborative Pianist/Private Music Instructor

**September 2016 - 2020** 

- Played for Choir Ensemble rehearsals and semester concerts
- Taught keyboard skills such as sign reading, technique, music theory, learning memorizing and repertoire.
- Introduced students to composer and music key to the development of music history and piano technique.

# **Duxbury Public Schools**, Collaborative Pianist/Private Music Instructor **August 2013 - June 2019**

- Concerts and Rehearsals (September 2013-June 2019) Music Director- Robert Judge
- Weekly rehearsals and yearly concerts for High School Choruses and Middle School Choruses: (High School- Chamber Singers, Concert Choir) (Middle School -6th Grade Chorus, 7/8th Mixed Chorus and ½ Concert Chorus)
- *Concerts* All Choral Night, Holiday Assemblies, Spring and Fall Concerts, and concerts at venues such as Carnegie Hall, Strathmore Hall, and Disney Springs in Orlando, Fl.

## **EDUCATION**

# **GENERAL ASSEMBLY**

Software Engineering Immersive

June 2022 - August 2022

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 12-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

#### **Masters of Music**

*Piano Performance*, University of Florida 2013

#### **Bachelors of Music**

*Piano Performance*, Texas A&M University-Commerce 2011

Awards- Graduate Assistantship, University of Florida